# **BORYANA ILIEVA**

Mohrenstr. 58 10117 Berlin German Institute for Economic Research bilieva@diw.de  $+49\ 30\ 89789\ 261$ 

Spandauer Str. 1 10117 Berlin Humbold University Berlin boryana.ilieva@hu-berlin.de

October 2017 - Present

October 2017 - Present

October 2014 - June 2017 Overall GPA: 1.4/5

2011 - 2014

2004 - 2009

grad. expected August 2023

weizsaecker@hu-berlin.de

### PERSONAL PROFILE AND RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a PhD candidate at the Humboldt University Berlin, Germany. Additionally, I am affiliated to the German Institute for Economics Research, DIW Berlin. My research focus is on labor, gender and behavioral economics. As a researcher, I have worked on micro-economic modelling, survey design, and empirical analysis of administrative and survey data based on both reduced form methods as well as dynamic structural models. I further have valuable international and private sector work experience. An open minded team player, excited by human psychology, technology, and innovation.

#### CURRENT EMPLOYMENT

**Humboldt University Berlin** 

PhD Candidate and Research Associate

Supervision and reference: Georg Weizsäcker

Microeconomic Theory and Applications Department &

Collaborative Research Center "Rationality and Competition"

German Institute for Economic Research, DIW Berlin

Research Associate and Teaching Fellow

Supervision and reference: Peter Haan phaan@diw.de

Public Economics Department

### **EDUCATION**

**Humboldt University Berlin** 

Master of Science in Economics and Management

Streams: Microeconomics, Econometrics, Business Analytics

International exchange scholarship:

September 2015 - January 2016

University Sankt Gallen, Switzerland

University of Mannheim

Bachelor of Science in Economics Overall GPA: 1.7/5

ERASMUS Scholarship: University Carlos III, Spain September 2013 - January 2014

Ruprecht-Karls University Heidelberg

2009 - 2011

Exam Grade: 1.5/1'Physikum' in Medical Science

1st German Language School "Prof. Konstantin Galabov", Sofia, Bulgaria

Secondary Education

Double Degree: German & Bulgarian

#### ACADEMIC WORK

- "Promotion prospects and within-level wage growth: A decomposition of the part-time penalty", job market paper
- "Biased Wage Expectations and Female Labor Supply" with Maximilian Blesch, Philipp Eisenhauer, Peter Haan, Annekatrin Schrenker, and Georg Weizsäcker
- "Selection effects and the distribution of the gender pay gap a novel approach" with Peter Haan and Christoph Breunig
- "Gender Gaps in Employment, Working Hours and Wages in Germany" with Katharina Wrohlich
- "What to expect when COVID-19 lockdown ends? Individual expectations about the labor market and re-openings in the Uited States" with Katharina Baum
- "Women, Fertility, and Informality" with Marianne Bernatzky Koehli and Lucas Finamor
- "Gender and Higher Education Decision in France" with Camille Ramigereau

## PRESENTATIONS, WORKSHOPS & GRANTS

#### 1. Presentations

"CRC Retreat" in Tutzing, Germany	October 2022
European Association of Labor Economics Conference 2022, Padova, Italy	$September\ 2022$
"CRC Retreat" in Tutzing, Germany	April 2022
Labor Economics Workshop, IHS Vienna	$November\ 2021$
Econometric Society Summer School in Dynamic Structural Econometrics	August~2021
ASSA, SABE Session "Gender Identity, Expectations, and Labor Market Outcomes"	January 2021
"Workshop on Subjective Expectations", Virtual, Laval University Canada	$December\ 2020$
"Joint IZA-IFS workshop", London, UK	$November\ 2019$
"CRC Retreat and Young Economist Workshop" in Tutzing, Germany	$September\ 2019$
2. Research Stay Grant	

Economics Department, Yale University, USA
Supervision and reference Cormac O'Dea

Spring 2020
cormac.odea@yale.edu

## 3. Research Grants

Supplementary Project Grant CRC Rationality and Competition, "Attitudes, Expectations and the Mediating Role of Political Action"

Supplementary Project Grant CRC Rationality and Competition, "Gender and Higher Education Decision in France"

### **TEACHING**

1. Structural Econometrics, Graduate level, Berlin School of Economics	2019 - 2022
2. Introduction to Microeconomics, Undergraduate level, Yale University Instructor: Cprmac O'Dea	Spring, 2020

2010

3. Macroanatomy, Undergraduate Level, University Heidelberg

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Academic

Chair of Econometrics, Humboldt University Berlin, Germany

Chair of Management, Humboldt University Berlin, Germany

April 2015 - August 2015

Collaborative Research Center "The Political Economy of Reforms"

April 2012 - July 2014

Mannheim, Germany

# **Private Sector**

Deutsche Bahn AG, Berlin, Germany Internship Management Consulting

April - July 2017

KPMG AG, Berlin, Germany
Internship Forensic Data Analytics

October 2016 - March 2017

Stocard GmbH, Ludwigshafen, Germany
Working Student International Customer Management
Internship Customer Analytics and Business Development

November 2014 - July 2015

June - October 2014

#### **SKILLS**

# Programming skills

Python, MatLab, R, Stata

# Languages

Fluent: Bulgarian, English, German

Other: Spanish (advanced), French (basic), Russian (basic)